Naomi Woodruff 206.651.1312 | naomi.woodruff@gmail.com | Seattle, WA linkedin.com/in/naomi-woodruff/ | github.com/naywood | https://naywood.github.io/newPortfolio/

CAREER SUMMARY

Full Stack Web Developer with a passion for UI/UX and front-end development with a background in Art. Encompasses an eye for detail, design and composition and never tires with learning new things. Known among colleagues for a positive attitude no matter the circumstances and creative design. Strengths in technical writing, social media management, bookkeeping, and user experience design.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

HTML/CSS, Javascript, Node.Js, Mongo, Mongoose, React.js, Express.Js, Github, VSCode, Bootstrap, Materialize, Bulma, Photoshop,

EDUCATION

Fullstack Web Development Certificate:University of Washington Continuing Education, Seattle, WA Associate in Arts and Sciences: Bellevue College, Bellevue, WA

PORTFOLIO

Frenemy | https://github.com/naywood/middle-ground | https://bipartisan.herokuapp.com/

- Frenemy is a place to connect with people on the opposite side of the political spectrum.
- Creative design of React functional and class based components, quality assurance of code via Github.
- Technology: TypeScript, NodeJS, Expresee, MongoDB, Mongoose, React, Passport, React-Materalize

Trails | https://github.com/naywood/Trails| https://trailsthehikefinder.herokuapp.com/

- A global trail searching app, with the intention of a place to connect with people for partners
- Design of user experience, created routes for all pages, and organized focus groups to plan task completion. Implemented critical thinking to how design would impact a user.
- Technology: NodeJS, Sequelize, MySQL DB, Express, Bulma

Musrch | https://github.com/naywood/musrchrrrrr | https://ajrice1018.github.io/musrchrrrrr/

- A music searching tool that brings all relative information (top YouTube videos, tour dates, band bio, link to purchase tickets) to you in one click.
- Created responsive grid based UI/UX with Materialize, mockups, and implemented creative design based on specifications provided by team members.
- Technology: HTML, CSS, Javascript, ¡Query, Ajax

EXPERIENCE

CODING INSTRUCTOR, CODING WITH KIDS; SEATTLE,

FEB 2019 - PRESENT

- Instructor at three different elementary schools teaching animation, game development, and coding using Scratch software to K-4th grade students in a classroom of nine students.
- Tailored communication based on skill level by demoing projects in class, facilitating conversations, teaching creative coding fundamentals, logic and functions to students.

FRONTDESK MANAGER, 1521 SECOND AVENUE; SEATTLE, WA

JAN 2018 - FEB 2019

- Frontdesk manager of a residential condominium building of 150 units. Assisted 90 full-time residents with management of their homes.
- Created content and design of monthly newsletters using Photoshop and emailed to all HOA and residents.

GALLERY COORDINATOR, BELLEVUE COLLEGE; BELLEVUE WA

SEPT 2015 - DEC 2017

- Coordinated five gallery shows and opening receptions per year of varying artistic mediums.
- Assisted individual artists with artwork placement and design of gallery layout to provide a visual impact.